310.488.3720

thejessicarudder@gmail.com github.com/jessrudder

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Respected leader with experience working on large-scale web applications. Passionate about fixing problems and optimizing code. Engages in independent study and continued professional development to keep up-to-date with the industry and to increase ability to tackle new challenges.

SKILLS

Ruby	Rails	Python
JavaScript	Backbone/Marionette	React
Public Speaking	PPC (incl. Adwords)	Curiosity

EXPERIENCE

Developer, Flatiron School

(2014 - Present)

- Built new onboarding flow which significantly reduced sign up friction using Ruby on Rails and React
- Implemented blogging feature to increase technical writing from students using Ruby on Rails, Backbone, Marionette and the Github API
- Utilized Object-Oriented CSS to update Learn.co app with consistent look (reducing amount of CSS by 70%)
- Boosted searchability of Learn app by creating keyword-rich, public-facing lesson pages
- Built and maintained static marketing websites using Ruby and Middleman

Account Manager – Search & Social, OMD Entertainment (2012 - 2014)

- Planned and managed implementation of North American-targeted search and social marketing campaigns for Disney's DVD releases
- Prepared and presented marketing plans and reports to VP-level stakeholders
- Spearheaded keyword strategy that boosted conversions by 15% and leading to adoption across all titles being sold with a digital format
- Implemented video campaigns on YouTube using inSearch, inStream and remarketing

Search Marketing Manager, MatchCraft

(2005 – 2012)

Coordinated with cross-functional team of engineers and client representatives to

- implement new programs and transition live programs without disruption of ad delivery
- Partnered with clients across nine countries (involving five languages) to identify needs and develop or refine online marketing programs to meet those needs
- Implemented taxonomy changes which improved on-time fulfillment by 20%
- Managed teams of direct reports and additional co-workers across two offices to achieve the defined goals for the marketing programs
- Grew largest program by 43% without increasing size of management team
- Streamlined team processes reducing account operating costs by 15%

Public Speaking

- Will it Inject: SQL Injection and Active Record Rails Conference https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2GHWAYys1is
- Diversity in Tech: Beyond the Hiring Process Ruby Conference AU https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2016-1489/diversity-in-tech-it-s-about -more-than-just-the-hiring-process-by-jess-rudder-1944
- Videos on Code Topics CompChomp https://youtube.com/compchomp

EDUCATION

Continuing/self-directed learning

- Emphases: critical thinking and technology
- Courses of study: formal logic, philosophy, computer programming, personal investing, artificial intelligence, drawing

Flatiron School

Full stack web development utilizing Ruby on Rails and JavaScript

New York University

B.A. Drama with training in stage productions, public speaking and literature

INTERESTS

general aviation (licensed), ultra running, computer programming, cooking, robotics, cycling